Guide to the Robert J. Cox papers, 1879-2010 RL.11794
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Robert J. Cox papers
1879-2010, bulk 1945-2010
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Cox, Robert J., 1933-
RL.11794
21.25 Linear Feet
The Robert J. Cox papers document his career as a journalist in Argentina and the United States as well as his personal life. The Robert J. Cox papers consist of correspondence, newspaper clippings, articles, event programs, magazines, journals, notes, administrative records, and photographs. The contents consist of Robert J. Cox's working files as a journalist as well as materials from his personal life. Major themes in the collection include journalism, human rights abuses, the Argentine Dirty War/El Proceso, the disappeared (los desaparecidos), censorship, human rights in Latin America, and Jews in Argentina.
Biographical / Historical
Robert Cox was born in England in 1933 and came to Buenos Aires as a young man in 1959. He worked as a journalist and eventually became the editor of the Buenos Aires Herald, the largest English-language newspaper in Argentina. Cox married Maud Daverio, who came from a prominent Buenos Aires family. They had five children.
At the Buenos Aires Herald, Cox wrote about the disappearances of left wing activists and extremists who were targeted by the Argentine military. He continued to cover the violence of the Dirty War/El Proceso even while receiving personal threats. Cox was honored with the Maria Moors Cabot Prize in 1978 for his reporting on Latin America.
Cox and his family fled Argentina in 1979 after his son Peter received an anonymous, detailed threat. After holding other positions, including a Nieman Fellowship at Harvard University, Cox become the assistant editor at The Post and Courier in Charleston, South Carolina. While in the United States, Cox continued to publish stories about the political landscape of Argentina as well. He also wrote at length about political violence in Central America and Cuba.
In 2008, his son David Cox published a book about his father's journalistic career in Argentina entitled Dirty Secrets, Dirty War: The Exile of Robert J. Cox (Buenos Aires, Argentina: 1976-1983).
The Buenos Aires Herald closed in 2017; their holdings are not widely archived elsewhere, so the copies of Herald materials in the collection may not be accessible in other institutions.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The Robert J. Cox papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2016.
Related Materials
Marshall T. Meyer papers, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University
Juan Méndez papers, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University
Patricia Murphy Derian Papers, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University
Memoria Abierta records, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University
Washington Office on Latin America records, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University
Jerome Shestack Papers, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University
Collection Overview
The Robert J. Cox papers consists of his working files as a journalist and personal life in both Argentina and later the United States. The Robert J. Cox papers comprises four series: the Correspondence series, 1964-2010; the Subject Files series, 1945-2010; the Writings series, 1945-2004; and Publications, 1879-2006. The Correspondence series includes Robert Cox's personal and professional correspondence from his career as a journalist. The Subject Files series consists of clippings, administrative records, and photographs. The Writings series consists of both published and unpublished materials written by Robert Cox and others. The Publications series consists of full-length magazines, pamphlets, and other publications; many of them include articles written by Robert Cox. Materials are in both English and Spanish.
Human Rights -- Argentina; Disappeared persons -- Argentina; Journalism -- Political aspects; Victims of state-sponsored terrorism -- Argentina; State-sponsored terrorism -- Argentina; Cuba -- Foreign relations -- United States; Montoneros Soldados de Perón (Organization: Argentina); Madres de Plaza 25 de Mayo (Rosario, Santa Fe, Argentina); Perón, Isabel, 1931-; Ejército Revolucionario del Pueblo (Argentina); Graiver, David, 1940 or 1941-1976; Human Rights -- El Salvador; Human Rights -- Guatemala; Abuelas de Plaza de Mayo (Rosario, Santa Fe, Argentina); Onganía, Juan Carlos; Alianza Anticomunista Argentina; Falkland Islands; Timerman, Jacobo, 1923-1999
- Correspondence, 1964-2010; 1
  Scope and Contents
  The Correspondence series consists of the personal and professional correspondence of Robert Cox. Much of the correspondence consists of everyday life and personal concerns. The files are arranged by correspondent or chronologically.
  - Alfredo Giorgi, 1980-1981 (Box 1)
  - Andrew McLeod Correspondence, 1984 (Box 1)
  - Charles Maechling, 1981-1982 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence (Box 1)
  - Correspondence fragments (Box 1)
  - Correspondence Regarding Disappearances, 1979-1984 (Box 1)
  - David Cox book, 2000 (Box 1)
    Correspondence between David and Robert Cox about David's book Dirty Secrets, Dirty War.
  - Death Threat to Peter, 1979 (Box 1)
    Although the threat is printed on Montoneros letterhead and is signed by the Montoneros, it is widely believed that the threat was authored by others.
  - Farewell Letters from Buenos Aires, 1979 (Box 1)
  - General Correspondence, 1964 (Box 1)
  - General Correspondence, 1967 (Box 1)
  - General Correspondence, 1968 (Box 1)
  - General Correspondence, 1969 (Box 1)
  - General Correspondence, 1971 (Box 1)
  - General Correspondence, 1972 (Box 1)
  - General Correspondence, 1973 (Box 1)
  - General Correspondence, 1974 (Box 1)
  - General Correspondence, 1975 (Box 1)
  - General Correspondence, 1976 (Box 1)
  - General Correspondence, 1977 (Box 1)
  - General Correspondence, 1978 (Box 1)
  - General Correspondence, 1979 (Box 1)
  - General Correspondence, 1980 (Box 1)
  - General Correspondence, 1981 (Box 1)
  - General Correspondence, 1982 (Box 1)
  - General Correspondence, 1983 (Box 1)
  - General Correspondence, 1984 (Box 1)
  - General Correspondence, 1985 (Box 1)
  - General Correspondence, 1986 (Box 1)
  - General Correspondence, 1987 (Box 1)
  - General Correspondence, 1988 (Box 1)
  - General Correspondence, 1989 (Box 1)
  - General Correspondence, 1990-1995 (Box 1)
  - General Correspondence, 1996-1999 (Box 1)
  - General Correspondence, 2000-2010 (Box 1)
  - Harry Ingham Correspondence, 1980-1993 (Box 1)
  - Henry Raymond Correspondence, 1984 (Box 1)
  - Letter from Kim Conway to Peter Bird Martin, 1981 (Box 1)
  - Letters to officials, Pineyro Pacheco and others, 1978-1980 (Box 1)
  - Maria Consuelo Castaño, 2000-2006 (Box 1)
  - Mario Amadeo, 1979 (Box 1)
  - Martin Robbins, 1985-1988 (Box 1)
  - Maud-S. de Moscattelli, 1984-2000 (Box 1)
  - Photocopy of letter from Teresa Hansen de Solari Yrigoyen to General Don Jorge Rafael Videla, 1976 (Box 1)
- Subject Files, 1945-2010; 2
  The Subject Files series consists of newspaper clippings, event programs, working documents, incomplete publications, research, and notes. Robert Cox kept together newspaper clippings and other materials that described events or individuals of interest to Cox. Some subject files were compiled during processing with documents with little context to guide arrangement. Subjects include Argentines living abroad, activism, Amnesty International, the Maria Moors Cabot prize, kidnappings, murders, Raúl Alfonsín, the Ejército Revolutionario del Pueblo (ERP), Las Malvinas/the Falkland Islands, David Graiver, the Inter American Press Association, the Mothers of the Plaza de Mayo (las Madres de la Plaza de Mayo), the Montoneros, Marshall T. Meyer, Uruguay, Jacobo Timerman, Carlos Saúl Menem, and journalism.
  - Adoption Certificate, 1977 (Box 2)
  - Committee to Protect Journalists and Humanitas International, 1980-1992 (Box 2)
  - CV - César Luis Díaz, n.d. (Box 2)
  - Haroldo Conti, n.d. (Box 2)
  - Nieman Foundation, 1980-1983 (Box 2)
  - Resolution of U.N. Subcommission on the Prevention of Discrimination and the Protection of Minorities, 1979 (Box 2)
  - South Africa, 1980-1982 (Box 2)
  - Universidad de Buenos Aires, Fordham Comision Fullbright Argentina Certificate, 1987 (Box 2)
  - Manuscript Fragments, n.d. (Box 2)
    Fragments from an unknown manuscript.
  - AAA, 1975 (Box 3)
  - ABC Perspective: Book Censorship in Chile Mary Helen Spooner, 1987 (Box 3)
  - Abuelas de Plaza de Mayo, n.d. (Box 3)
  - Adolfo Perez Esquivel, 1980 (Box 3)
  - Alfredo Bravo, 1977 (Box 3)
  - Amalia Bouchard, n.d. (Box 3)
  - Americans gone Missing in Latin America, 1972-1982 (Box 3)
  - Amnesty International, 1976-1986 (Box 3)
  - Amnesty International - Argentinians in Peru, Juan Méndez, 1980 (Box 3)
  - Anglo-Argentines, 1966-1970 (Box 3)
  - Anti-Defamation League, 1983 (Box 3)
  - Apocalypse Now, n.d. (Box 3)
  - Arbiza, n.d. (Box 3)
  - Argentina - 1983 elections (Box 3)
  - Argentine American Forum, 1979 (Box 3)
  - Argentine Economy, 1985-1987 (Box 3)
  - Argentine timeline, 1977 (Box 3)
  - Arocena case, 1977 (Box 3)
  - Asociacion de Periodistas de Guatemala, 1988 (Box 3)
  - Branca Case, 1985-1988 (Box 3)
  - Buckley on Argentina, 1977 (Box 3)
  - Buenos Aires Herald - Critique of format, 1994 (Box 3)
  - Buenos Aires Herald - Staffing and Finances, 1969 (Box 3)
  - Buenos Aires Herald - Vision, mission, n.d. (Box 3)
  - Bunge Corporation, 1974-1975 (Box 3)
  - Cabot Award, Verbitsky, 2001 (Box 3)
  - Cadena Informativa - Los Secuestros de un Historietista y un Periodista, 1977 (Box 3)
  - Carlos Suarez Mason, 1988 (Box 3)
  - Cartoons, n.d. (Box 3)
  - CELS, 1989-1991 (Box 3)
  - Central America - Nicaragua, 1986-1988 (Box 3)
  - Chile, 1985-1988 (Box 3)
  - Clippings, 1960-1969 (Box 3)
  - Clippings, 1970 (Box 3)
  - Clippings, 1971 (Box 3)
  - Clippings, 1972 (Box 3)
  - Clippings, 1973 (Box 3)
  - Clippings, 1974 (Box 3)
  - Clippings, 1975 (Box 3)
  - Clippings, 1976 (Box 3)
  - Clippings, 1977 (Box 3)
  - Clippings, 1978 (Box 3)
  - Clippings, 1979 (Box 3)
  - Clippings, 1980-1989 (Box 3)
  - Clippings, 1990-1999 (Box 3)
  - Clippings, 2000-2010 (Box 3)
  - Clippings, undated (Box 3)
  - Clippings and about assassination of Pedro Eugenio Aramburu, 1970 (Box 3)
  - Clippings about murders and kidnappings, 1974-1978 (Box 3)
  - Clippings about Robert Cox and Alfonsín, 1980-1983 (Box 3)
  - Colonel Juan Alberto Pita, 1976 (Box 3)
  - Comisión Interamericana de Derechos Humanos de la Organización de los Estados Americanos, 1980 (Box 3)
  - Comite Judio Americano, 1980 (Box 3)
  - Cuba, 1990-1994 (Box 3)
  - Cuba Conference, 1984-1992 (Box 3)
  - Cuba Conference - Photographs and Postcards, 1989-1990 (Box 3)
  - Cuba - Political Dissidents and Press Freedom, 1999 (Box 3)
  - Disappearance of Graciela Antonia Rutilo Artes and Carla Graciela Rutilo Artes, 1981-1983 (Box 3)
    The folder includes a document created by Matilde Artes Company, mother of Graciela Antonia Rutilo Artes. It describes the circumstances of the latter's kidnapping in 1976 as well as Company's experiences with the Bolivian, Peruvian and Argentine governments.
  - Disappearance of Nicolás Miguel Angel Román, n.d. (Box 3)
  - Economia Argentina, 1975-1977 (Box 3)
  - Eduardo Jozami, 1981-1983 (Box 3)
    Jozami was a lawyer and journalist arrested by the military in 1976.
  - El Salvador: A Los Sacerdotes, n.d. (Box 3)
  - Engagements, 1979-1989 (Box 3)
  - ERP, Santucho, Anti-guerrilla forces, undated (Box 3)
  - Europeos Desaparecidos y Asesinados en la Argentina, n.d. (Box 3)
  - Falklands, 1982-1983 (Box 3)
  - Familiares de Desaparecidos, 1977 (Box 3)
  - Familiares de desaparecidos y detenidos por razones políticas Roberto Jorge Santoro, n.d. (Box 3)
  - Fiat - Beaumont Kidnapping, 1977 (Box 3)
    Coverage of kidnapping of Fiat director Luchino Reveli-Beaumont.
  - Firing Line - Argentina After Peron, 1977 (Box 3)
  - Free Expression and Global Media: Barriers and Boundaries Notes, 1992 (Box 3)
  - Fund for the Free Expression Forum Torture Argentina, 1980 (Box 3)
  - General Ramón Camps, 1977-1988 (Box 3)
  - Graiver Case - Gelbard, 1976-1977 (Box 4)
    Clippings and wires related to the Graiver, Aluar, Lanus case which involved money laundering to finance leftist groups.
  - Habeas Corpus, Amnesty, 1976-1978 (Box 4)
  - Hector Hidalgo Sola, 1977 (Box 4)
    Includes editorials by Cox regarding the disappearance of Argentina's ambassador to Venezuela.
  - Hirsch, n.d. (Box 4)
  - H. Menchi Sabat, n.d. (Box 4)
  - Honors received by R. Cox, 1979-1981 (Box 4)
  - Horacio Verbitsky, n.d. (Box 4)
  - Horatius Political cartoon, n.d. (Box 4)
  - Human Rights and American Foreign Policy, 1981 (Box 4)
  - Informe Sobre Libertad de Prensa en la Argentina, n.d. (Box 4)
  - Institute of the Americas, 1983 (Box 4)
  - Inter-American Commission on Human Rights - Editorial Perfil S.A. and Diario Perfil S.A. (Box 4)
  - Inter American Press Association, 1982-1988 (Box 4)
  - Inter American Press Association - Board of Directors Directory and Charter, Bylaws and Rules, 1983-1988 (Box 4)
  - Inter American Press Association - Midyear meeting San Antonio, Texas, March 1987 (Box 4)
  - Inter American Press Association - Report of the Committee on Freedom of the Press and Information, 1992 (Box 4)
  - International League for Human Rights, 1989-1991 (Box 4)
  - Invitation to Awards Ceremony for Robert Cox, n.d. (Box 4)
  - Isabela Perón, 1974-1976 (Box 4)
  - Jacobo Timerman, 1976-1999; 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Jorge Novak to Archbishops of Executive Commission of the Organization of American States (O.E.A.), 1982 (Box 4)
  - Jorge Salimei Case, 2002 (Box 4)
  - Journalism Organizations and Rights, 1982-1990 (Box 4)
  - Juicio a las Juntas, 1985 (Box 4)
  - Kidnapped Lawyers, 1977 (Box 4)
  - Kidnappings, Disappearances, 1976-1978 (Box 4)
  - La Republica Uruguay, 1990 (Box 4)
  - Lectures, Conferences, Cabot Award, 1978-1980 (Box 4)
  - Letter from Prisoners of Villa Devoto, 1980 (Box 4)
  - Lista No. 4 (Disappeared?), n.d. (Box 4)
  - Lo Que Usted No Sabe De la Guerilla, n.d. (Box 4)
  - Luis Adolfo Prol Montamat, 1980-1982 (Box 4)
  - Madres de Plaza de Mayo, 1982-1987 (Box 4)
  - Madres de Plaza de Mayo Línea Fundadora, 2001-2002 (Box 4)
  - Malvinas Falkland Islands, 1982 (Box 4)
  - Marshall T. Meyer, 1972-1984 (Box 4)
  - Maud Cox and Amnesty International, 1983-1986 (Box 4)
  - Miscellaneous-Clippings, press, correspondence, 1977-2002 (Box 4)
  - Miscellaneous Photos, 1964-1978 (Box 4)
  - Missing Journalists, 1977 (Box 4)
  - Montoneros, Extremist Groups, 1973-1977 (Box 4)
  - Montoneros prisoners, n.d. (Box 4)
    Photographs of two men near a Montoneros banner that appear to be captive.
  - Moors Cabot Award, 1978 (Box 4)
    Includes congratulatory letters from Emilio Mignone and Marshall Meyer.
  - New York Latin Americanist Conference, 1982 (Box 4)
  - Otto Kauders In Memoriam, 1977 (Box 4)
  - Padre Carlos Magica, 1974 (Box 4)
  - Padré Castellani, n.d. (Box 4)
  - Perón, 1964-1966 (Box 4)
  - Peronist Workers Youth JTP, 1974 (Box 4)
  - Peter Manigualt, 2003 (Box 4)
  - Photos - Nicaragua, Sandistas, Chamorro, 1984 (Box 4)
  - Photographs of Robert Cox, 1957-2002 (Box 4)
  - Photos unidentified, n.d. (Box 4)
  - Presentation by Gabriel García Márquez to the General Assembly of the InterAmerican Press Society, 1996 (Box 4)
  - Presentacion por Patricia Feeney Seminario Solaridad Internacional, 2007 (Box 4)
  - Press in Argentina and A Terrorist Anatomy of Murder (Box 4)
  - Press, Terrorism, Latin America, 1981-1982 (Box 4)
  - Propaganda against Straus, 1975-1982 (Box 4)
  - Principles and Procedures to be Followed by Mass Communication Media (Box 4)
  - Public Program on Human Rights, 1981 (Box 4)
  - Pubs. on military, subversion, 1969-1976 (Box 4)
  - Relatives of the Disappeared, 1976-1983 (Box 4)
    This file includes mailers from Amnesty International and forms from Familiares de desaparecidos detenidos por razones politicas.
  - Robert Cox CV and Bios, 1981 (Box 4)
  - Second International Seminar Argentine-American Forum (ISAAF) (Box 4)
  - Segundo Informe de Onuven, 1985-1989 (Box 4)
  - SIP Interamerican Press, 1980-2002 (Box 4)
  - Speech to IAPA 57th General Assembly, 2001 (Box 4)
  - Speech-International Press Institute, 1980 (Box 4)
  - Speech by Robert Cox at International Press Institute - 29th General Assembly, 1980 (Box 4)
  - Tango Lyrics, n.d. (Box 4)
  - Terror from the Left, n.d. (Box 4)
  - Terrorism, 1979 (Box 4)
  - Terrorist Clippings, 1975-1977 (Box 4)
  - Testimonio de Eliana Naom de Wenner, n.d. (Box 4)
  - Tex Harris, 1977-1984 (Box 4)
  - Texto de la Conferencia pronunciada por el Secretario Ejecutivo del Consejo Nacional de Desarrollo, Señor Bernardo Crinspun, en la Escuela Nacional de Guerra ante Autoridades de la Junta Interamericana de Defensa, 1965 (Box 4)
  - Timelines, undated (Box 4)
    Timelines of the rise of the military Junta up through the 1983 elections which restored democracy to Argentina.
  - Transcript BBC Panorama Broadcast, 1978 (Box 4)
  - Tucuman, 1975-1976 (Box 4)
  - Tweedale Fellowship, 2001 (Box 4)
  - Ultima Clave - Información Politica Semanal, 1977 (Box 4)
    Special issue of Ultima Clave dedicated to kidnapping of its subdirector, Rodolfo Férnandez Pondal.
  - United States State Department Documents about Threat received by Cox Family, 1976-1979 (Box 4)
  - Uruguay Coordination Group Amnesty International, 1985-1986 (Box 4)
  - Uruguay - Ferreira detention, 1984 (Box 4)
  - Uruguay - Michelini Case, 1976 (Box 4)
  - Venezuela, 2002 (Box 4)
  - Violence (mostly FFAA), 1976-1978 (Box 4)
  - V.S. Naipaul, 1972-1981 (Box 4)
  - Who is Inspiring the Death Squad, n.d. (Box 4)
  - Woodrow Wilson Center, 1981 (Box 4)
  - Cox Exile, 1979 (Oversize-box 7)
  - Desaparecidos, 1977-1979 (Oversize-box 7)
  - La Prensa, 1945-1946 (Oversize-box 7)
  - Marshall Meyer, 1987-2003 (Oversize-box 7)
  - Montoneros Guerillas, 1977 (Oversize-box 7)
  - Naipaul, 1972-1977 (Oversize-box 7)
  - Terrorism: The Challenge to the State Symposium and No más agresiones a los periodistas posters, 1982 (Oversize-box 7)
  - Cox - Bio Materials, 1980-1982 (Oversize-box 8)
  - Amnesty International, 1983-1984 (Oversize-box 9)
  - Robert Cox Arrest, 1977 (Oversize-box 9)
  - Buenos Aires Herald, 1960-1969 (Oversize-box 9)
  - Buenos Aires Herald, 1970-1979 (Oversize-box 9)
  - The living revolution American Revolution Bicentennial, 1976 (Oversize-box 10)
  - Buenos Aires Herald, Part 2, 1970-1979 (Oversize-box 10)
  - Buenos Aires Herald, 1980-1989; 2 folders (Oversize-box 10)
  - Buenos Aires Herald, 1990-1999 (Oversize-box 10)
  - Aluor-Lanusse Case, 1977 (Oversize-box 11)
  - Aramburu, 1978 (Oversize-box 11)
  - Argentina World Press Coverage, 1980-1983 (Oversize-box 11)
  - By About Cox, 1977-2005 (Oversize-box 11)
  - Chile, 1987-1990 (Oversize-box 11)
  - Clippings, 1978 (Oversize-box 11)
  - Cox in the Foreign Media, 1973-1975 (Oversize-box 11)
  - Economia Argentina, 1975-1977 (Oversize-box 11)
  - El Salvador, 1982-1991 (Oversize-box 11)
  - Falklands, 1982 (Oversize-box 11)
  - General Oversized Clippings, 1966-2004 (Oversize-box 11)
  - Isabela Peron, 1974-1976 (Oversize-box 11)
  - Jacobo Timerman, 1971-1992 (Oversize-box 11)
  - Juan Perón, 1950-1974 (Oversize-box 11)
  - Juicio Contra las Juntas, 1985 (Oversize-box 11)
  - La Opinion, La Nacion (Argentine news media), 1945-1980 (Oversize-box 11)
  - Moors Cabot Award, 1978 (Oversize-box 11)
  - News and Courier, 1981-2004 (Oversize-box 11)
    Later The Post and Courier.
  - Nicaragua, Central America, 1982-1983 (Oversize-box 11)
  - Other Argentine Media Clippings, 1973-1985 (Oversize-box 11)
  - Schoenfeld and La Prensa, 1980-1981 (Oversize-box 11)
  - SIP Interamerican Press, 2001-2002 (Oversize-box 11)
  - Timerman, Jews, 1976-1981 (Oversize-box 12)
  - Walter Klein, 1978-1979 (Oversize-box 12)
  - Amnesty Action, 1982-1984 (Oversize-box 13)
  - Cuba - Body of Salvador Allende; Pepe Abrantes, 1990 (Oversize-box 13)
  - James Nielson, 1980 (Oversize-box 13)
  - Juan Domingo and Eva Perón, 1972-1974 (Oversize-box 13)
  - La Republica, Vocero De La Democracia Argentina En El Exilo, 1980-1982 (Oversize-box 13)
  - Madres de la Plaza de Mayo, 1985 (Oversize-box 13)
  - Marshall Meyer, 1977-1988 (Oversize-box 13)
  - News Coverage of Argentina, 1965-1969 (Oversize-box 13)
  - Papel Prensa, 1977 (Oversize-box 13)
  - Pérez Esquivel, 1980-1981 (Oversize-box 13)
  - Juicio Contra la Junta - Press Coverage, 1985 (Oversize-box 14)
  - Menem Presidency, 1990 (Oversize-box 14)
  - Buenos Aires Herald, 2000-2010 (Oversize-box 15)
  - General Clippings, 1970-1979 (Oversize-box 15)
  - General Clippings, 1980-1989 (Oversize-box 15)
  - General Clippings, 1990-1999 (Oversize-box 15)
  - General Clippings, 2000-2010 (Oversize-box 15)
  - El Diario del Juicio 1 and 2 (photocopy), 1985 (Oversize-box 16)
  - Foreign News Clippings, 1972-1988 (Oversize-box 16)
  - Other Argentine Media Clippings, 1973-2002 (Oversize-box 16)
- Writings, 1950-2004; 3
  The Writings series consists of writings by Robert Cox and other individuals. The writings include published and unpublished; drafts of published works were organized with their published counterpart when possible. The published material written by Cox appeared in numerous publications predominately from Argentina or the United States. There are journalistic pieces along with government or non-profit/NGO reports. A notable feature of the series is the written work of colleagues and researchers investigating journalism in Latin America, especially Argentina, and United States human rights policy.
  - Wires and Cables, 1950-1993; 5
    The Wires and Cables subseries consists of cables. The cables largely consist of news wires, both from within Argentina and internationally. Authorship is not always clear in the messages of the cables, but there are cables written by Cox and other journalists. The content of the cables covers news from Buenos Aires and the provinces. The content of the cables largely cover Argentine politics, the Dirty War/El Proceso, the Madres de la Plaza de Mayo, the disappeared, Juan Perón, the Montoneros, David Graiver, terrorism, kidnappings, and Isabel Perón. The subseries is arranged chronologically. The majority of the cables appear to cover the 1960s and 1970s.
    - Graiver Case, 1976-1977 (Box 1)
    - Wires, 1950-1959 (Box 1)
    - Wires Part 1, 1960-1969 (Box 1)
      Guerilla Army activities, Economy - Meat, Meat Strike.
    - Wires Part 2, 1960-1969 (Box 1)
    - Wires Part 3, 1960-1969 (Box 1)
    - Wires Part 1, 1970-1979 (Box 1)
    - Wires Part 2, 1970-1979 (Box 1)
    - Wires, 1980-1989 (Box 1)
    - Wires, 1993 (Box 1)
    - Wires - Cables, 1972-1977 (Box 1)
    - Wires, undated; 4 folders (Box 1)
      Most undated wires or cables look as if they are from the 1960s or 1970s.
  - Journals and Personal Notes, 1977-1979; 2
    The Journals and Personal Notes subseries consists of unpublished writings authored by Robert Cox. Subjects covered by the notes include Jacobo Timerman, torture, Marshall T. Meyer, Montoneros, threats, and the Buenos Aires Herald. The subseries is arranged by subject matter or format.
    - Address book, n.d. (Box 5)
    - 1979 Calendar (Box 5)
    - Marshall Meyer, n.d. (Box 5)
    - Notes, n.d.; 3 folders (Box 5)
    - Personal Notes - Montoneros, n.d. (Box 5)
    - Reflection about early years of Cox at the Buenos Aires Herald, n.d. (Box 5)
    - Small Notebooks, n.d.; 3 folders (Box 5)
    - Torture, Timerman Writings, n.d. (Box 5)
    - La Prensa, n.d. (Box 6)
    - Notebooks, n.d.; 4 folders (Box 6)